<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hot Takes on StandingPad&#39;s Corner</title>
    <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/tags/hot-takes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hot Takes on StandingPad&#39;s Corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 20:55:49 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://standingpadanimations.github.io/tags/hot-takes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Songs of War Has Always Been Dead; Just Let It Rest in Peace For Once</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/songs-of-war-is-dead-let-it-rest-in-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 20:55:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/songs-of-war-is-dead-let-it-rest-in-peace/</guid>
      <description>On June 14th, 2020, Black Plasma Studios announced the plan to cancel Songs of War Seasons 2 and 3, an animation series 5 years in the making, with a story uncontested by anything else. Among the reasons cited include lack of revenue, lack of viewership, and burnout.
Of course, people were understandbly upset, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t accept the inevitable.
Almost 3 years later, there are still people who can&amp;rsquo;t accept that Songs of War is dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Take: We&#39;re Teaching People to Treat Help Channels like Google</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/issues-with-helping-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 18:58:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/issues-with-helping-too-much/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s spent a good amount of time in a help channel on a Minecraft animation server can related to this; you go on help and support, and see the following:
One person asking how to import Optifine shaders That guy using 2.79 who gets offended when you politely suggest updating to a new version The person who wants to import animation from a youtube video (I swear I&amp;rsquo;m not making this up) 50 people asking why material mode is so slow 10 more people asking how to show textures 1 or 2 people asking how to move bones (seriously guys?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
