<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MCprep on StandingPad&#39;s Corner</title>
    <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/tags/mcprep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MCprep on StandingPad&#39;s Corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 16:52:29 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://standingpadanimations.github.io/tags/mcprep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prepping Api Cleared! Now What?</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/prepping-api-cleared-now-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 16:52:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/prepping-api-cleared-now-what/</guid>
      <description>Just yesterday I gave the greenlight for Prepping API, a proposal that would allow users to create their own prep material functions in Python.
But is it worth it?
That proposal was made in 2022, and for about a year now I&amp;rsquo;ve spent time thinking about how such an API could be secured. The problem is obvious: this API would allow arbitrary Python scripts to be loaded.
Sandboxing? Not in Blender where we have only pure Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Dropping 2.7x Support in MCprep is for the Better</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/dropping-27x-support-in-mcprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 21:09:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/dropping-27x-support-in-mcprep/</guid>
      <description>After years of supporting Blender 2.7x in MCprep, we&amp;rsquo;ve now decided to remove support starting with MCprep 3.5.
Hardcore Blender 2.7x user walks in
&amp;ldquo;WHAT THE F-CK DID YOU SAY!?!?!? Reverse it, NOW!&amp;rdquo;
Yeah no, we&amp;rsquo;re not doing it. It&amp;rsquo;s too much work to suppor-
&amp;ldquo;Sounds like something a lazy developer would say&amp;rdquo;
Shut up, this is for the better, let me explain.
The Massive Pain That is, 2.7x Support When we say &amp;ldquo;2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems of MCprep Development</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/problems-of-mcprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 16:05:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/problems-of-mcprep/</guid>
      <description>As the MCprep 3.4.2 release date draws nearer, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to remind users how MCprep development works, and how important it is that MCprep receives supports from the community. I feel like people have forgotten how much work goes into MCprep, and I think a little reminder wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt.
Overview Currently, MCprep only has 2 active maintainers (TheDuckCow and myself). While the MCprep GitHub repo says there&amp;rsquo;s 7, most of them haven&amp;rsquo;t contributed in a while: Now obviously TheDuckCow would have the most commits (411 at the time of writing this) since he&amp;rsquo;s been working on MCprep for almost 10 years now (yes, MCprep has been around for 10 years), with myself being behind with 96 commits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCprep Progress</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/mcprep-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 18:54:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/mcprep-progress/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: As of March 11th, 2023, most of these are now confirmed for the 3.4.2 release
As some of you know, I&amp;rsquo;m an MCprep developer, and as part of what I do I work on adding features and fixing bugs in MCprep. Not that, I also help review pull requests and fix bugs.
The latest version of MCprep, MCprep v3.4.1 was released in August of last year. While it may seem like MCprep development is dying, that couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
