<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>StandingPad&#39;s Corner</title>
    <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on StandingPad&#39;s Corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 21:09:38 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://standingpadanimations.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Dropping 2.7x Support in MCprep is for the Better</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/dropping-27x-support-in-mcprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 21:09:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/dropping-27x-support-in-mcprep/</guid>
      <description>After years of supporting Blender 2.7x in MCprep, we&amp;rsquo;ve now decided to remove support starting with MCprep 3.5.
Hardcore Blender 2.7x user walks in
&amp;ldquo;WHAT THE F-CK DID YOU SAY!?!?!? Reverse it, NOW!&amp;rdquo;
Yeah no, we&amp;rsquo;re not doing it. It&amp;rsquo;s too much work to suppor-
&amp;ldquo;Sounds like something a lazy developer would say&amp;rdquo;
Shut up, this is for the better, let me explain.
The Massive Pain That is, 2.7x Support When we say &amp;ldquo;2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems of MCprep Development</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/problems-of-mcprep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 16:05:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/problems-of-mcprep/</guid>
      <description>As the MCprep 3.4.2 release date draws nearer, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to remind users how MCprep development works, and how important it is that MCprep receives supports from the community. I feel like people have forgotten how much work goes into MCprep, and I think a little reminder wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hurt.
Overview Currently, MCprep only has 2 active maintainers (TheDuckCow and myself). While the MCprep GitHub repo says there&amp;rsquo;s 7, most of them haven&amp;rsquo;t contributed in a while: Now obviously TheDuckCow would have the most commits (411 at the time of writing this) since he&amp;rsquo;s been working on MCprep for almost 10 years now (yes, MCprep has been around for 10 years), with myself being behind with 96 commits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCprep Progress</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/mcprep-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 18:54:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/mcprep-progress/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: As of March 11th, 2023, most of these are now confirmed for the 3.4.2 release
As some of you know, I&amp;rsquo;m an MCprep developer, and as part of what I do I work on adding features and fixing bugs in MCprep. Not that, I also help review pull requests and fix bugs.
The latest version of MCprep, MCprep v3.4.1 was released in August of last year. While it may seem like MCprep development is dying, that couldn&amp;rsquo;t be further from the truth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EndorCore Is Shutting Down</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/endorcore-shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 18:41:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/endorcore-shutdown/</guid>
      <description>On Feburary 11th I&amp;rsquo;ll be shutting my Discord bot EndorCore down.
Background A couple of years back, I coded a Discord bot using the Discord.py framework. It was the primary way I learned Python, and it was a blast while it lasted, but all good things some to an end.
Why For starters, EndorCore is no longer maintained. The last commit on the Github repo was in March of 2022. Because of this, EndorCore has slowly started to lose functionality as time passed and Discord changed the API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I did It: Calm After the Storm</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/calm-after-storm-render/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 18:19:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/calm-after-storm-render/</guid>
      <description>Yes guys, I&amp;rsquo;m back.
Anyways, I recently had an idea and made this render: Not my best, but lets talk about how I made it.
Trees of Light For this, I used Bforartists 3.4, which is based off of Blender 3.5. Immediately I noticed a slowdown in viewport responsiveness. Thinking it was a driver, I went from Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s Studio drivers to their Game Ready drivers, but no difference.
Sidenote: Nvidia has 2 drivers, Studio and Game Ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell for Now</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/goodbye-for-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 13:16:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/goodbye-for-now/</guid>
      <description>I just don&amp;rsquo;t know how else to put it, I&amp;rsquo;m leaving the Minecraft animation world. After what David RB has done, I feel that it&amp;rsquo;s not right for me to continue.
For anyone that hasn&amp;rsquo;t heard, David RB, the original owner of Black Plasma Studios, has recently been exposed for being abusive and grooming a minor.
I initially refrained from making a stance, but after reviewing the evidence released by Posidon, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I can no longer refrain from making a stance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Songs of War Has Always Been Dead; Just Let It Rest in Peace For Once</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/songs-of-war-is-dead-let-it-rest-in-peace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 22:18:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/songs-of-war-is-dead-let-it-rest-in-peace/</guid>
      <description>On June 14th, 2020, Black Plasma Studios announced the plan to cancel Songs of War Seasons 2 and 3, an animation series 5 years in the making, with a story uncontested by anything else. Among the reasons cited include lack of revenue, lack of viewership, and burnout.
Of course, people were understandbly upset, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t accept the inevitable.
Almost 3 years later, there are still people who can&amp;rsquo;t accept that Songs of War is dead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Take: We&#39;re Teaching People to Treat Help Channels like Google</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/issues-with-helping-too-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 18:58:15 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/issues-with-helping-too-much/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s spent a good amount of time in a help channel on a Minecraft animation server can related to this; you go on help and support, and see the following:
One person asking how to import Optifine shaders That guy using 2.79 who gets offended when you politely suggest updating to a new version The person who wants to import animation from a youtube video (I swear I&amp;rsquo;m not making this up) 50 people asking why material mode is so slow 10 more people asking how to show textures 1 or 2 people asking how to move bones (seriously guys?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Did It: 2023 New Year&#39;s Render</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/new-years-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/new-years-2023/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s now New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, so I made a new years render: This is perhaps the most complicated render I have done to date. I started just before Christmas and finished in about 3 to 4 days.
Hologram Shenanigans One of the things I wanted to do was 3D holograms, because I&amp;rsquo;ve never done that before. I first followed a Blender Guru tutorial, and the final node setup does essentially the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Jason the Cat</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/meet-jason-the-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 21:37:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/meet-jason-the-cat/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys, just a small IRL update, my family got a cat today! His name is Jason and he&amp;rsquo;s 8 months old. Here&amp;rsquo;s some photos:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/happy-holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 13:30:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/happy-holidays/</guid>
      <description>Happy holidays everyone! Sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t post yesterday (it was my dad&amp;rsquo;s birthday and birthdays + Christmas Eve don&amp;rsquo;t really mix well).
Of course, I myself don&amp;rsquo;t celebrate Christmas (cultural reasons) so I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for New Years. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a New Years render, so here&amp;rsquo;s a WIP
It&amp;rsquo;s also the second week of winter break for me, which means in about a week I&amp;rsquo;ll have to return back to doing IRL stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Did It: Hacking Holograms Render</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/scale-render-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 16:16:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/scale-render-process/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the motivation to make the following render
As you can see, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of reflections, some long test, volumetrics, and other stuff. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t do much Minecraft rendering anymore, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll impart some insight into some of the more technial bits.
GCC&amp;rsquo;s Time to Shine &amp;ldquo;GCC?&amp;rdquo;
Basically, I needed to make a lot of text. Now, I could slam my keyboard a couple of times, but as a nerd I felt like it was the perfect oppertunity to use C++ to generate long text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cycles Optimization: The Magic Behind Scrambling Pixels like Eggs</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/automatic-scrambling-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 04:30:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/automatic-scrambling-distance/</guid>
      <description>After I made my post yesterday regarding samples and light bounces, I was asked by a buddy a pretty interesting question.
I try to avoid making certain settings seem &amp;ldquo;magical&amp;rdquo; because with all magic, there&amp;rsquo;s a downside. For GPU rendering (sorry CPU renderers, this setting brings no benifit to y&amp;rsquo;all), one of these settings is known as
Automatic Scrambling Distance
While this setting does help with render times a lot, it also requires a lot of tweaking to make it render with little artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cycles Optimization: Spewing Samples and Bouncing Around like Crazy</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/cycles-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 12:17:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/cycles-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We know Cycles is a pain in the butt to render. Specifically, the long render times. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s tons of videos that talk about what settings to use, but those videos don&amp;rsquo;t explain what the settings do. So, exactly what settings do what?
Samples What are samples? In a nutshell, samples are rays, and the sample count represents how many rays are released by Cycles per pixel+ of the camera (yes Cycles starts from the camera as an optimization, all optical systems can be reversed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving On</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/moving-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 19:59:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/moving-on/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys, I think yall might be confused why I&amp;rsquo;ve created a new website, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it.
But first, what&amp;rsquo;s been going on recently?
Well in short, chaos. The actual situation is much longer, but to put it simply Twitter is no longer (in my opinion) a sustainable platform to remain on, so I moved to Mastodon.
Now because Mastodon allows you to verify your own sites, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone ahead and made this new one, since I felt like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me 3D Artist MCprep Developer Creator of the Rendor Programming Language and Resurgence Virtual Machine Pakistani-American Ahmadi Muslim Here&amp;rsquo;s some of my work </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/renders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/renders/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some of my work </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
