<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>StandingPad&#39;s Corner</title>
    <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on StandingPad&#39;s Corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://standingpadanimations.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I Did It: 2023 New Year&#39;s Render</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/new-years-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/new-years-2023/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s now New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, so I made a new years render: This is perhaps the most complicated render I have done to date. I started just before Christmas and finished in about 3 to 4 days.
Hologram Shenanigans One of the things I wanted to do was 3D holograms, because I&amp;rsquo;ve never done that before. I first followed a Blender Guru tutorial, and the final node setup does essentially the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet Jason the Cat</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/meet-jason-the-cat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 21:37:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/meet-jason-the-cat/</guid>
      <description>Hey guys, just a small IRL update, my family got a cat today! His name is Jason and he&amp;rsquo;s 8 months old. Here&amp;rsquo;s some photos:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/happy-holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 13:30:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/happy-holidays/</guid>
      <description>Happy holidays everyone! Sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t post yesterday (it was my dad&amp;rsquo;s birthday and birthdays + Christmas Eve don&amp;rsquo;t really mix well).
Of course, I myself don&amp;rsquo;t celebrate Christmas (cultural reasons) so I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting for New Years. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a New Years render, so here&amp;rsquo;s a WIP
It&amp;rsquo;s also the second week of winter break for me, which means in about a week I&amp;rsquo;ll have to return back to doing IRL stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Did It: Hacking Holograms Render</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/scale-render-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 16:16:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/scale-render-process/</guid>
      <description>I recently had the motivation to make the following render
As you can see, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of reflections, some long test, volumetrics, and other stuff. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t do much Minecraft rendering anymore, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll impart some insight into some of the more technial bits.
GCC&amp;rsquo;s Time to Shine &amp;ldquo;GCC?&amp;rdquo;
Basically, I needed to make a lot of text. Now, I could slam my keyboard a couple of times, but as a nerd I felt like it was the perfect oppertunity to use C++ to generate long text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cycles Optimization: The Magic Behind Scrambling Pixels like Eggs</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/automatic-scrambling-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 04:30:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/automatic-scrambling-distance/</guid>
      <description>After I made my post yesterday regarding samples and light bounces, I was asked by a buddy a pretty interesting question.
I try to avoid making certain settings seem &amp;ldquo;magical&amp;rdquo; because with all magic, there&amp;rsquo;s a downside. For GPU rendering (sorry CPU renderers, this setting brings no benifit to y&amp;rsquo;all), one of these settings is known as
Automatic Scrambling Distance
While this setting does help with render times a lot, it also requires a lot of tweaking to make it render with little artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cycles Optimization: Spewing Samples and Bouncing Around like Crazy</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/cycles-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 12:17:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/cycles-optimization/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We know Cycles is a pain in the butt to render. Specifically, the long render times. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s tons of videos that talk about what settings to use, but those videos don&amp;rsquo;t explain what the settings do. So, exactly what settings do what?
Samples What are samples? In a nutshell, samples are rays, and the sample count represents how many rays are released by Cycles per pixel+ of the camera (yes Cycles starts from the camera as an optimization, all optical systems can be reversed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving On</title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/moving-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 19:59:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/posts/moving-on/</guid>
      <description>Hi guys, I think yall might be confused why I&amp;rsquo;ve created a new website, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about it.
But first, what&amp;rsquo;s been going on recently?
Well in short, chaos. The actual situation is much longer, but to put it simply Twitter is no longer (in my opinion) a sustainable platform to remain on, so I moved to Mastodon.
Now because Mastodon allows you to verify your own sites, I&amp;rsquo;ve gone ahead and made this new one, since I felt like it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me 3D Artist MCprep Developer Creator of the Rendor Programming Language and Resurgence Virtual Machine Pakistani-American Ahmadi Muslim I&amp;rsquo;m not actually female, this is just my OC
Here&amp;rsquo;s some of my work </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/renders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://standingpadanimations.github.io/renders/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s some of my work </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
